

# JENNA WESTENDORF

Program Manager and Frontend Developer

## **PROFILE**

Whether I worked in education, social work, or nonprofits, my career has always focused on advancing the capacity for people and organizations to achieve positive impacts. I am a highly motivated, self-driven team-builder, educator, and outdoor enthusiast committed to continuously learning. I value working with a cohesive and trusted team towards creating a more equitable and inclusive world.

#### CONTACT



Sacramento, CA



jenna.westendorf@gmail.com

(916) 995-4351



/jenna-westendorf



#### **EDUCATION**

San Francisco State University Masters in Social Work, 2018

**University of California, Berkeley** BA Interdisciplinary Studies, 2013 Emphasis: Disparities in Education

**CERTIFICATION:** Responsive Web Development (CSS, HTML, JavaScript, React)

## **SKILLS**

- HTML, CSS, JavaScript, GitHub, wireframes, responsive web design, APIs
- 13+ years community-building and effectively leading teams
- 15+ years of experience learning about and addressing educational disparities and working for social justice
- Exceptional communication, problem-solving and multitasking abilities
- Successful at working in team environments as well as independently to deliver quality results

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

**Course Director/Trainer/Lead Instructor** | Outward Bound | CA and UT FEB 2015 – PRESENT

- Led teams of staff to design, develop, and facilitate courses 6-50 days in length
- Supported staff professional development -- co-developed new instructor training programs for two Outward Bound schools, trained over thirty new staff, facilitated both virtually and in-person program-wide trainings, provide on-the-job coaching and mentorship
- Collaborated with and supported all operations within the organization, including program management, logistical, and instructional staff
- Communicated student progress, course progress, and staff and program strengths and areas for development through written reports and direct feedback

**School Social Worker** | Tucson Unified School District | Tucson, AZ SEP 2023 – MAY 2023

 Worked as an integral part of the school team to assess and address all student and staff needs and foster social-emotional learning throughout the school community

#### First Responder

AUG 2016 - JAN 2020 | Rock Medicine | Bay Area, CA

Collaborated with team to provide immediate, emergency response during crisis

**Community Partnership Director** | Magnolia Project | Berkeley, CA MAY 2010 – JUNE 2011

- Networked with community organizers and coordinated community-based projects
- Recruited, interviewed, and trained 40 participants for summer service trip, internship, and exchange programs
- Co-facilitated weekly board meetings
- Expanded community partners in New Orleans and throughout the Bay Area